Well, hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number ninety seven in this exercise, we are going
to implement and create that algorithm quick sort and Jeff.
So for that, we go to this our secret folder in our project and algorithms.
I will create Java class, so-called quick sort.
By the way, you can download all of these source codes that we have created before in the previous
exercises under the Resources folder and that every exercise.
OK, whatever.
So this is that quick sort of class that we are going to work with.
So first of all, we need to create a function for swapping the elements, so swapping their elements.
I will create public static void swap function.
It took into the parameter, the array that we are going to switch its elements.
So the first index is I and the first the second element is Jason, where are we going to swap that
elements at index with the elements of the with the element of that index?
We are getting this and this phases of the array elements and we are going to swap these values.
So in them.
Afraid that we have created many times in the previous videos.
It stores a temporary variable.
That value of that index eye and array at index and now becomes equal to array took the value of that.
And next J and the Array and Index J now becomes equal to that.
This way, we have swept that to add ons.
The second step is here, the second step is a function that takes last element as pivot place is the
pivot element at its correct position in sort of a and the place is all smaller, smaller than the pivot
to the left of the pivot and all greater elements to the right of the pivot.
This is that this is a part of of this algorithm that we saw.
So we need to make two functions the part the chin and that a quick sword method.
This part, the chin will help us to divide the smaller elements from the pivot to the left and the
greater elements of the pivot to the right.
OK.
To the right of the pivot.
So this is the function called Partridge.
So as I told you, this function will text element aspect.
For that, I will create a public static int it returns a variable of type and called part.
The chin and a A are the end, low and end.
OK, now.
We will create the element, pivot and pivot equal to array at index high.
We have learned in the previous videos that we took that most dried element of the array as a pivot.
OK, you can take a random pivot, the random element, OK, but for for for like standardizing our
algorithm and making it very, very simple, we took that pivot as the most tried element of that.
Every.
OK.
We start by making a falou start from age equal to low and less, then stops at less than or equal to
high, reaching the end minus one because the last element is the pivot that we have to get.
And the J Plus, plus what we need to do to check if the current element is smaller than that pivot.
If current element is smaller than the pivot, that pivot, OK?
So if are they at Index J less, then a pivot pivot.
So make and increment index of the smaller element ie plus plus and then call the method here, which
is here we have best int i equal to low minus one low minus one, the index of the smaller element and
indicates the right position of the pivot sound so far.
OK, so i plus plus then swap call the method swap.
We passed the error a r and I and J.
OK.
This is.
This is their index of small, smaller element.
OK, and indicates the right position of the pivot found so far, and we have called this method sweeping
it.
OK, now we need to call the method swab again in order to swab the elements of my last one and with
the high.
OK, and then returning that I +1 I plus one.
OK.
This is very simple.
We have created and a method that they use the last element as the pivot and places the pivot element
to its correct position inserted the array and the place is all the smaller and all the smaller smaller.
Then they pivot to the left of the pivot and all the grades or the greater of then their pivot to the
right of it.
OK, now the main function that will implement the quick sort is here.
So the public static void, quick sorting I was quoted something to to differentiate it from the class
name and a a r and low and high.
OK.
If they are checking if low, low, less than high, then make a by IS partitioning index.
And are they index B is now at the right place?
I will create an integer B by a partition called the method a R and low and high.
These are their indices.
This will partition the pie.
Why is the partitioning index OK?
So I will make a comment here by is there for the tuning index?
OK, now separately, sort elements before the partitioning and after partitioning I set to you quick
sort algorithm is one of the divide and conquer algorithms.
So following that, divide and conquer algorithms use recursion to make this sort.
But here there is a trick that we need to do sort of the left substrate and the right summary.
For that, I will call that quick sorting algorithm.
This is the recursion
quick sorting algorithm will be a method will be called the first time at low and five minus one.
And the second time quick sorting algorithm will be called again.
And but this time is by +1 and high.
OK.
This is the low and the first time we make it quick sorting for the left.
SUMMARY And this time we will make a quick sorting for that right somebody.
And we will add them later on by joining them because they have reached the single app.
Now, in order to print at bay, I will call the method three four, but then think of that very public
void.
Brent, then they it will start in here.
They are on and size.
We can make it like this for and equal to zero I
I look that we can make.
This is in C we can in Java.
We can get the addresses directly by making this array and order size length.
And I plus plus,
we look through all the elements to print them.
They are and I last space system out that prime alarm.
This is for printing, they're not the driver code in Java will be a method of public static void main
static game.
Strange, they called
and after a year are equal to that we are going to sort of let me.
OK.
We call the method quick sorting.
We passed that, Ray, the First Amendment, but then the zero, the low and the high is an oversized
minus one, which is a are the length minus one
system that allowed the brain alarm so that every.
But in the Adam brand.
This is the method called print.
Public static, I would make static.
I didn't think print out a
print of a hopes that's happening.
This is static.
Sorry.
Static.
Print out they we passed.
They are right.
OK, now let's around and see our quick sort algorithm in chief.
And there we go, this is the sorted array, and this is the past.
So we have sorted this correctly and in quick.
So by the way, the algorithm complexity of that time complexity of it is in the best case.
Worst case would be analog and also to analog and and in the worst case would be oh to and squish.
OK.
And power too.
This is that time complexity for this quick sorting.
By the way, you can practice this.
I want from you to practice this code.
Dude, I did just start testing it to make it changed the way that it is making like ascending, descending,
starting from high to low, low, from to high and so on.
So play with this code in order to understand it and read write them down in your copy book.
And I want from you to practice them.
Well, because quick sort is one of them most and the frequently asked questions in the universe at
the exams and that.